[English subtitles are available]
[My Journey to You]
[Episode 12]
I heard from the servants
that you didn't eat much dinner.
I was afraid you would be hungry.
So I made some cakes
and tea.
They can help to calm your nerves.
I wanted to go to the clinic
and get some herbal medicines which help to calm nerves.
But since the Gong residence became heavily guarded,
Young Master Yuanzhi
has placed many restrictions on the acquiring of medicine in the clinic.
So I went to the kitchen,
took some ready-made food,
and made some mimosa flower tea for you.
Don't bother.
Let's eat together.
Chat with me.
Young Master,
are you still thinking about Lady Lan?
Since childhood, I thought
I was observant
and sensitive.
But it turns out
I never knew what my parents were thinking.
And my brother who died.
It seems
that I never really knew them.
You suddenly lost your father and brother
and became the Sword Wielder.
And in a short time,
you have to pass three trials.
Murders also happened again and again in the Gong residence.
You must be very stressed.
No matter how stressed I am,
I can't say I'm tired
or complain.
I can't
let people think I'm incompetent either.
Otherwise,
people who are in the shadows
will take advantage of it.
You can tell me
about your suffering.
Although
I'm not good at speaking
and don't know how to comfort you,
I can be your listener
or sing for you.
You're not good at speaking?
You're eloquent.
But
even if you're a caring flower,
I don't want
to make you worry.
No caring flower
minds listening to people's problems.
You don't understand.
Growing flowers and grasses isn't easy.
If people keep complaining,
they won't flourish.
Really?
Of course.
It's like if you keep saying bad words
to a glass of water,
the water will become cloudy.
Are you lying?
I'm not lying to you.
So,
the same goes for growing flowers.
What should people say to flowers?
We should
praise her for her beauty,
praise her for being thoughtful,
praise her for being lovable,
praise her for being sensitive,
and praise her for having eyes
which are like stars.
Flowers also have eyes?
I'm not talking about flowers.
You're blushing.
It's late.
You should rest early.
I'm leaving.
She really got shy.
It doesn't work.
There's half a month left.
What should I do?
Why are you still here?
This is my home.
Why should I leave?
Why did you
keep looking at the tiger embroidery just now?
You were in a trance.
That belonged to his younger brother.
Is he Brother Lang whom you mentioned
just now?
Yes.
Why can you always hear our conversations?
You like eavesdropping, right?
You should ask yourself
if you're coming to the Jue residence
too often.
Is it uncomfortable to live in the Zhi residence?
It's proper for me
to come and see my future husband.
You're almost an adult.
Find a wife.
Don't pester your brother every day.
Mind your own business.
It doesn't matter.
If you don't tell me,
I'll ask him later.
Don't ask him.
If you ask, he'll remember the sad thing again.
What is the sad thing?
My brother
had a biological younger brother
who he loved the most.
Aren't you the younger brother
who he loves the most?
In his heart,
no one can compare to Brother Lang.
Mother.
Oh.
Young Master Shangjue.
You're here to pick up your mother and brother again?
I don't know if it's a boy or a girl.
Mr. Jingjie said it's my brother. Then it's my brother.
Okay. It's your brother.
Shangjue.
Which one do you like?
The little tiger.
You're an elder brother now.
In the future,
take good care of your younger brother.
Sure.
Brother, I want to practice using knives too.
You're still a kid.
You'll hurt yourself.
Brother, this dagger looks good.
Great!
I can also practice using knives.
Then
why have I never seen Brother Lang?
Ten years ago,
he and Lady Ling
were both killed by people from the Wufeng.
Anyway,
don't ask around.
Young Master Shangjue.
Leave it.
Why are you here?
The servants heard something
being broken.
They dared not come in.
They were afraid that they would offend you.
But you dared to come in?
I'm scared too.
But I know
no matter how angry you are,
there should be someone
in the room serving you.
Besides,
I know
although you look scary,
you're actually very gentle.
Come here.
Give me your hand.
How do you know
my hand was scratched?
The smell.
I've been in the martial world for years.
I'm very sensitive to the smell of blood.
Do you still think I'm gentle?
It's just a minor injury.
Fingers and hearts are inseparably linked.
It hurts.
I have to say it.
If you say it, will your hand stop hurting?
If you say it,
will the wound heal without medicine?
No.
But when I was a child,
every time I skinned my knees,
my mother
would...
When she was applying medicine for me,
she said,
"Qian, if it hurts,
tell me."
Every time my mother told me this,
the wound
didn't hurt that much.
Isn't it good
to be cared about?
The world of children
is different from the world of adults.
In the martial world,
happiness and prestige
can be shared and shown.
But pains and secrets
cannot be revealed.
So people
often laugh with others.
But few people
cry with others.
Few.
But not zero.
If you bury the wounds in your heart
and touch them
again and again,
you'll have more scars.
Have you ever seen wounded beasts?
They don't show their wounds to others.
Because the weak cannot be tolerated in the colony.
They just find a dark cave
and lick their wounds quietly,
waiting for recovery
or death.
But humans are not beasts.
Beasts have no hearts,
but humans do.
A heart
must have a place to stay.
If you have someone
who can boil snow and warm alcohol for you,
even if it's not bright and hot enough,
it'll be enough for you to spend the winter in your heart.
But not everyone in your heart
will warm up a bottle of alcohol for you.
Maybe
he'll leave a scar
on your heart.
Go to the clinic
tomorrow.
The minor injury isn't serious.
That's not what I meant.
Hmm?
Your hands are hot.
The temperature of your hands isn't normal.
It's caused by either sickness
or poison.
I caught a cold a few days ago.
I'm feverish.
Have you taken medicine?
No.
After Elder Yue was killed,
people need Young Master Yuanzhi's permission
to come in and out of the clinic.
The rules on the acquiring of medicine are stricter.
Take my token
and ask the doctor
to give you the medicine you request.
This token is...
In the Gong residence,
you're allowed to go everywhere.
Thank you, my lord.
This box contains
some of your father's old things.
I didn't give it to you before
because I didn't want you to be sad
when you see it.
Now,
I should give it to you.
New Snow leans on Taiyuan.
Start from New Snow.
Use strength at the Taiyuan acupoint.
The wrists are the most flexible
and the moves
are the fastest.
Air Frost.
Use strength at the Chize acupoint.
Using elbows to keep control is the most effective.
As for Cold Wave, using strength at the Yunmen acupoint
can stimulate all the energy and blood in the upper body
and increase the pressure of the knife.
You began to practice at dawn.
Did you learn it from an expert
or figure it out by yourself?
I learnt it from an expert.
Xue Chongzi.
In order to ask you to take him out for fun,
he helped you cheat.
I learnt it from my father.
Former Sword Wielder?
What a bad day.
You promised
that you would find Anonymous within ten days.
The deadline is up.
Logically speaking,
Young Master Shangjue
should come to the Yu residence and report it to me.
But I was worried
Young Master Shangjue didn't find the truth
and was ashamed to see me.
So,
I specifically came here to ask you.
It's not that he is too ashamed to see you.
He just doesn't want to see you.
My brother has already found something.
He's going to the Council of Elders and reporting it.
Really?
I've found out
the identity of Anonymous.
I was going to
discuss it with the elders.
Since you
came here in person,
I can tell you first.
But I don't know
if you
can take it.
There are three suspects.
The first one
is the leader of Yellow Jade guardians.
The second one
is the housekeeper of the Council of Elders.
But these two people
are temporarily cleared.
Then there's
the third suspect left.
Lady Wuji.
You were pushed so hard
so you want to frame her, right?
Hey.
We have proof.
When you questioned my blood
in the Council of Elders,
you also had proof.
What?
Weren't you given a slap in the face?
That's why
we won't let you gloat again.
Besides,
we also want you to know
how a slap in the face feels.
We interrogated all the guardians
who were on guard that night
and found out
that no one knew where the three people were
on the night Elder Yue was killed.
And these three people
could approach Elder Yue easily.
Then why are you only suspecting Lady Wuji?
Why don't you hide
your ulterior motive?
What's the rush?
He hasn't gotten to the point yet.
According to the rules of the Gong family,
our servants and guardians
were all selected from Jiuchen Valley.
Most of the people in the valley
have been living there for generations.
They don't know martial arts.
It's hard to find spies from the Wufeng
there.
The leader of Yellow Jade guardians
and the housekeeper of the Council of Elders
are both from Jiuchen Valley.
For this alone,
they were cleared?
That's too arbitrary.
You're right.
According to my style,
I sent some people
to investigate their backgrounds.
The leader of Yellow Jade guardians
is Jin Yunfeng.
His surname used to be Qian.
His family ran a clinic.
Because of his strong body,
when he was seven,
he was chosen to enter the Gong residence
and trained as a guardian.
Later, he was granted the surname Jin.
The ancestors of the housekeeper Hu Hai
were carpenters.
Ten years ago,
he started working in the kitchen of the Council of Elders.
He had been working hard for many years
before being promoted
to the housekeeper of the Council of Elders.
These two people's families
have been living in Jiuchen Valley for generations.
But Lady Wuji is different.
Lady Wuji
became Lady Lan's servant before she married into the Gong family.
She's obviously an outsider.
Of course she's the most suspicious.
What's more ridiculous is
that her identity as a servant is fake.
She's not from the Gusu family.
Before entering the Yang family,
her identity
is unknown.
What's interesting is
that the year she entered the Yang family
and became Lady Lan's servant
was exactly the year the former Sword Wielder,
your father Gong Hongyu,
was attacked by people from the Wufeng
near the Yang family's mansion.
Everything you said
is just your conjecture.
I can also say
because you failed to threaten Lady Wuji
and have a grudge against her,
you're deliberately slandering her.
If you really want to accuse her,
show me evidence.
You said it yourself.
Arguing
is quite boring.
It'll only make you
petty people who want to use this chance
to take revenge.
We dare to say this
because we have a witness.
In the later investigation,
both Jin Yunfeng and Housekeeper Hu
had alibis.
Only Wuji
had no alibi.
She said
she's old.
She went to bed early.
It was cold at night in winter.
She didn't open the door and the windows.
She didn't want to catch a cold.
She also specially asked the servants
not to disturb her unless something happened.
What Lady Wuji said is not wrong.
No one can prove
what they haven't done.
I've also told you
if you really want to accuse her,
show me solid evidence.
Witnesses
and physical evidence.
Don't worry.
I'll have evidence.
As long as I keep investigating...
Keep investigating?
Ten days are up.
You failed to keep your promise.
You haven't passed
the Trial of the Three Realms either.
There's not
much time left.
If you continue to be idle,
you'll lose the position
of the Sword Wielder.
Since neither of us
kept our promise,
we're even.
I hope
you can find solid evidence.
Otherwise,
don't waste time in pestering Lady Wuji.
I don't need you to teach me how to investigate.
But you.
Do you need me to teach you
how to pass the next two trials?
I heard you quarreling
outside.
It doesn't matter.
Why are you here?
I heard from the servants
that you've been tired
and haven't slept well recently.
These days,
you often wake up in the early hours of morning to light candles.
There's a kind of pillow
which can help to calm nerves in my hometown.
It's made from Huangyang Mu.
Putting some scented leaves
which are boiled by Wuteng soup
can help you to calm your nerves and sleep well.
If I can find it for you
from the market,
you'll sleep well
at night.
You've entered the Gong residence.
Don't always think about outside things.
If you really need anything,
ask the servants to buy it.
Of course.
Of course...
The bride of the Gong family
can't go in and out at will.
I know the rules.
I just wanted to say
since Young Master Yuanzhi is here,
I just wanted to ask
if I can go to the clinic
to see if there are these things.
Go quickly.
I have something to tell my brother.
Yes.
Brother.
Lady Wuji is cunning
and deceived us.
If she stops committing these crimes,
if we want to get evidence–
She won't stop.
Because her mission hasn't been completed yet.
You know her mission?
No.
But it’s not as simple as just
assassinating Elder Yue.
Let’s wait for her next move.
You have already adjusted
the security of the Gong family
and added so many
hidden guards invisible to the eyes.
If she kills again,
she will definitely give herself away.
But I won't allow her to kill again.
Every drop of blood of the Gong family
cannot be trampled by outsiders.
Ten years ago,
the promise I made gritting my teeth,
I will definitely keep it.
Miss Yun.
You can't enter
without Young Master Yuanzhi's command.
I'm sick.
Can't I see a doctor?
You can.
Miss Yun, please return home first.
I will send a doctor
to your residence
to take your pulse and prescribe medicine
and send the herbs back to Yu Lineage later.
Miss Shangguan.
Young Master Shangjue gave me his token
to me.
He asked me to come collect some medicine.
Understood.
You put the stones in front of the clinic.
How bold of you.
If I didn't put it in an obvious place,
I'm afraid you won't come.
The fire is burning you up
and you're trying to get some medicine
but can't, right?
I did though.
I can give you some.
You're so kind?
Thank you, then.
Don't be anxious, sister.
Take a walk with me.
He's really biological?
Yes.
It seems that in terms of blood,
it's difficult to find a breakthrough point for Gong Shangjue.
If Gong Ziyu
can pass the trials successfully,
his position as the Sword Wielder
will be concrete.
You pretended to cooperate
and gave me that half of the medical case.
But secretly,
you joined hands with Wuji
to humiliate Gong Shangjue in front of the Council of Elders.
At the same time,
you also made yourself
even more likeable to Gong Ziyu.
You're amazing.
Let's do it according to our capabilities.
You call that according to our capabilities?
Aren't you afraid of implicating me?
When you forced me to get the medical record
to please Gong Shangjue,
you didn't consider my situation.
Your internal skill is in disorder.
The burning of the Fortnight Flies
doesn't feel good, does it?
The skill I practice is extremely yin
and clashes with the burning poison directly.
No matter how painful it is,
it's just a disorder in my internal skill.
Meanwhile, the skill you practice is extremely yang
and you can't even bring up your internal skill.
You must be more uncomfortable than I am.
But the medicine
is in my hands now.
Either
be obedient and cooperate with me,
or
be tortured slowly.
These herbs
can only suppress the poison temporarily.
As soon as the fortnight comes,
we still have to leave the Gong Residence
to get the antidote from the person sent.
Otherwise,
we'll all die.
It's just a matter of time.
I will definitely find a way out.
Do you even believe
what you said?
It must be hard to live
under the nose of Gong Shangjue.
You don't even dare to show your tail.
Why don't you give me the medicine?
I'll go exchange them for you.
I've found a way out of the Gong Residence.
What did you say?
Thank you, Sister.
Can you give me the medicine?
Yes.
But...
we don't have enough herbs.
You're going back on your words?
You underestimate me.
I never go back on my words.
Go to the clinic
with me again.
Thank you.
Look at my memory.
I forgot these herbs.
I have to
thank Sister Yun for reminding me.
[Shang]
Eldest Young Miss.
It's so hard.
So hard.
Why praise me?
It's so hard.
Eldest Young Miss.
Why are you working here alone again?
Where are your servants from the Shang residence?
They don't treat you like a lady at all.
That's outrageous.
Tell me.
Do you want me
to go knock some sense into them?
On what basis?
You're just a craftsman.
Take this
to knock on the roof
to see where's leaking.
What are you doing?
It's so lethal.
You're amazing.
This must be the hidden weapon you just invented?
This is the dessert I made for Jin Fan.
What did Jin Fan do wrong?
He doesn't deserve this, does he?
Shut up!
Eldest Young Miss,
how long has it been since you last did research with me?
Things like research
require persistence.
You can't be distracted by these things,
especially men.
Stay away from men.
Otherwise,
you will encounter misfortune.
Then why are you
so close to me?
I don't count.
You're a lady disguised as a man?
I'm a real man of seven feet.
Do not insult me.
I'm sorry.
Hey!
Look at you.
You're so impatient.
Girls
should be gentle like a spring,
and reserved like a stone.
Look at you.
You're so loud.
What kind of impression are you leaving for Jin Fan?
Your words are like knives,
cutting into my heart.
Look at your dirty face.
Your beauty
has been covered by the clouds.
Xiaohei,
you're not only considerate,
but also have good taste.
What smells so good?
Hoho.
You have good taste too.
I boiled this handkerchief
in wintersweet on low heat
for a whole night.
The smell lingers
and is refreshing.
You are a man of seven feet
using a fragrant handkerchief?
You have a problem.
Who?
You.
Who stinks?
-You stink.
-Who has a problem?
You have a problem.
Although I'm a craftsman,
I take personal hygiene very seriously
and clean myself too.
All right. Got it.
Stay away from men.
Yes.
Otherwise, I will encounter misfortune.
Hey!
Don't just listen to just this line!
Give it to me.
I'll go out
to get the antidote for you.
Give this to Hanya Qi for me.
What is this?
Gong Yuanzhi's hidden weapon.
I've drawn a sketch
and retrieved the fragments.
It can help Wufeng research
what kind of poison it is on it.
A Gong family hidden weapon
can be bought at a price on the outside.
You can get the antidote
with just this?
You haven't opened up and researched on
Gong Yuanzhi's hidden weapon pouch?
I thought you'd have at least
opened it and took a look.
If I opened it up to research on it
before sending it to you,
you would have been locked up in the prison by now.
You're right.
I should thank you.
The hidden weapons used by Gong Yuanzhi himself
is different from from the normal Gong family secret weapon
that can be bought outside.
It's way more lethal.
The structure is also exquisite.
It's like a craftsman's artwork.
What?
Gunpowder.
Gunpowder?
In the hidden secret weapon,
there's a firing pin
and gunpowder.
When triggered with collision,
it will explode,
causing the metallic blade with the poison to activate a second time.
It can even penetrate armor.
Looks like
you should be able to get the antidote.
What about you?
How is the map coming along?
I'm still short of a lot.
However,
my main takeaway is,
the direction Wufeng was going towards previously was wrong.
The front hill is not the focus.
The most important place in the Gong Residence
is the back hill.
Sir.
Yong Master Yuanzhi.
This is the prescription Miss Shangguan Qian just took.
Two?
She also got a serving for Miss Yun.
You may leave.
Is there any problem with the prescription?
It looks...
like two servings of
medicine that can help cool one's body down.
Medicine?
What happened?
What else could it be?
Jin Fan...
insulted me.
Don't you think you're being too harsh with your words?
I don't think he's that kind of person.
That's who he is.
You know a person's face,
but not their true nature.
What is this?
Today is the Lantern Festival.
I wanted to make him a box of delicate cakes.
I've been working
since morning.
I worked so hard yet he didn't eat anything.
Could it be...
because Guardian Jin is vegetarian
so he's not eating the meat puffs?
This is peach blossom pastry.
Maybe he's allergic to peach blossoms–
This is peach blossom pastry?
How hurtful, Miss Yun.
I'll go teach Guardian Kim a lesson later.
Whatever this is,
it's a gift from you.
My sincerity was returned
with coldness.
Eldest Young Miss.
When I see you making desserts,
it reminds me of my childhood.
Every year on the Lantern Festival,
there will be many delicate pastries sold on the streets every year.
Jujube cake,
osmanthus candy,
dragon's beard candy,
and even salted-egg yolk filling glutinous rice balls.
So many?
There should be some in the
Jiuchen Valley's market too.
Other than
the difference in customs at the borders,
the Lantern Festival
is well-celebrated everywhere.
Jiangnan, Saibei,
Bashu, Jiangliu,
there will be lanterns everywhere.
Thousands of families bustle with the music,
and the lanterns continue for over ten miles.
This talks about the Lantern Festival.
Eldest Young Miss,
haven't you visited the Lantern Festival?
No.
Since I was young,
I have never been out.
What a pity.
I remember a poem.
The colorful sky shines on the ground,
the lights stud the sky.
It looks like stars falling,
and the moon hanging.
It talks about how
people enjoy the lanterns and the moon,
sing and dance.
Young men and women
will express their feelings to each other
on this romantic day.
You've read so many novels.
Do they not talk about it?
They do.
Yes, they do.
Every year at the Lantern Festival,
girls
will dress up nicely.
Because it is said that
it's on this night,
that you'll most likely meet your destined one.
The destined one?
In the sea of lanterns,
people's heads flutter.
If you can meet someone
you like on this night,
it's fate.
Do you know
what the last sentence
of the poem I said just now is?
The laughter of young ladies
sound before the thousand lights.
I can imagine
you shine brightly
under the fireworks.
Fireworks?
Jin
Fan!
Come quickly!
What are we waiting for?
Unfortunately,
we can't go out.
Gong Ziyu.
Gong Ziyu!
Can you be softer?
People who don't know would think
you have great internal skill
and can shout across a thousand miles.
Your voice is so loud.
There are fewer birds in the yard recently too.
Jin Fan.
Sit.
Do you know
what day it is today?
The Lantern Festival?
Guess again.
Are you trying to say
it's a big day for you and Jin Fan?
Do you think I am
someone who only thinks about
love and laugh all day long
and not do my job?
You are.
Today is the big day
we celebrate your passing of
the first trial.
It was the day before yesterday.
No matter which day it was, we have to celebrate it.
A good meal is never too late.
Good girls don't slack off.
To celebrate your success,
let's go to the market tonight.
It's inappropriate
to leave the Gong Residence at this time.
Miss Yun wants to go too.
Really?
You want to go too?
Sure.
Let's go then.
But Miss Yun,
as a foreign bride,
the elders
wouldn't allow her to leave the palace, right?
If it will cause inconvenience
to the Sword Wielder,
I won't go.
I can celebrate the festival alone too.
Enjoy your celebration.
No need to ask the elders for things like this.
I know the secret passage to leave
the Gong Residence.
Miss Yun.
Let's go.
Let's get changed.
It'll be dark in the secret tunnel.
I will hold your hand.
We haven't reached the secret tunnel yet.
Why is he holding her in such a hurry?
I heard it's dark inside.
Hold me tight.
I'm scared too.
That's why you have to hold me tightly.
Then I'm more scared.
Should I report it?
He's the Sword Wielder.
Who are you going to report it to?
Young Master Shangjue is in charge of things outside of the Gong residence.
We'll report it to Young Master Shangjue.
Young Master Yuanzhi.
What a beautiful lantern.
Young Master Shangjue was born in the year of dragon.
This must be for Young Master Shangjue.
My brother doesn't like useless things like this.
But
I thought it'd be nice
to make the room brighter
on the Lantern Festival.
You made it yourself?
Where is my brother?
I'm here to eat with him.
Young Master Shangjue and Miss Shangguan Qian
are already having dinner.
The servants
started a fire at the the backyard's pavilion.
They should be there.
Would you like to have dinner with them together?
Let me go report this to Young Master Shangjue first.
No need.
Understood.
Young Master Shangjue normally eats alone.
Why did you
invite me to dinner today?
Today is the Lantern Festival.
We should
celebrate.
In the past,
you must've gone shopping and watched shows,
admire the stars and the moon,
and lanterns
with your relatives and friends.
Right?
I wasn't in good health when I was young.
I didn't go out often.
The Lantern Festival at the Gong Residence
is not as happening.
I thought you might not be used to it.
Just right,
I'm done with my work,
so I came to accompany you.
You must have suffered a lot
marrying into the Gong family.
One may suffer
But marrying Young Master Shangjue
does not make me suffer at all.
Actually,
you don't like crowds, do you?
No I don't.
Then I don't like it either.
Can you change
what you like?
Of course.
People develop likings
after they are born.
But hatred can be born with.
Some people are born
with hatred.
Yes.
In this world,
there is no love for no reason,
but there is hatred for no reason.
The two people who may not have met before
can be enemies.
Gong family has many enemies.
Your enemy
is my enemy.
You're good at talking.
Am I wrong?
You just said
my enemy
is your enemy
instead of
Gong family's enemy
is your enemy.
Is there any difference?
No.
The top row
is the prescription for Yun Weishan.
The next row
is Shangguan Qian's prescription.
It can't be just a simple medicine.
There must be something wrong with it.
Bulbophyllum Thouars,
Fern-leaf corydalis.
Angelfish orchid.
Naked Star Bug.
Bulbophyllum Levinei.
Young Master Shangjue,
would you like to try some?
I've been decocting
this medicine all afternoon.
On top of that...
with brown-core cape jasmine,
Chinese liquorice that has budded,
and amber with caterpillar fungus.
With just cinnabar and saltpeter,
this will be lethal.
This is lethal.
Brother!